Ahmad M. Mustapha

Phone Number: +961 71 177 395 E-mail: ahmad.m.mustapha@hotmail.com

Δ	h	^		ŧ	M	le
_	u	u	u		ıv	

I offer a skill set that is rarely found, combining roles as an Al Engineer, Backend Developer, and System Designer. My experience spans both academia and industry, covering a wide range of domains including Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Data Science, and Backend Development. I thrive in roles that challenge me to think creatively, solve complex problems, and apply strong analytical skills.

Education

From 2024 to present	American University of Beirut (AUB) Doctoral Researcher	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2018 to 2020	American University of Beirut (AUB) Master in Electric and Computer Engineering Major in Machine Intelligence GPA: 4	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2015 to 2017	Lebanese University Master in Information systems and Data Intelligence Rank: 1/13	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2012 to 2015	Lebanese University Bachelor in Computer Science	Beirut, Lebanon
Experience		

From 2024 to Present Al Lead

Holonox

- Lead and contributed to the development and maintenance of a multiservice application
- Set up the architecture
- Flask, Django, Docker, Al APIs

From 2023 to Present

Founder and Lecturer

- Mustapha Technology Institute Seasonal Side Gig
 - Educational startup to fill educational gaps
 - Taught and developed learning materials
 - E.g. Intro. to machine learning Online presence for developers – Intro to Python – CV building

From 2022 to 2023

Career Break

Traveled – Learned New Language

Beirut, Lebanon

Beirut, Lebanon

From 2024 to 2022	Java Davalanar	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2021 to 2022	 Java Developer Murex Maintained a business module Agile Methodology Java, Python, Spring, Spring Boot, Open API, REST, 	Deliut, Lebanon
From 2020 to 2021	 Machine Learning Engineer Veer Managed a Machine Learning project from A to Z The project was related to Traffic Management Data Cleaning, Data Munging, Data Visualization Prediction. Python, RNNs, LSTMs, Regression, Pandas, NumPy, Plotly, Dash. 	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2018 to 2020	 Research Assistance American University of Lebanon (AUB) Implementing/Improving Bleeding Edge Unsupervised Deep Learning Models Neural Networks Adversarial Samples Unsupervised Deep Learning Software Engineering Interaction with Machine Learning 	Beirut, Lebanon
From 2018 to 2020	 Multidisciplinary Engineer Self-Employed – Different Clients Computer vision models to detect vehicles in a tropical reserve in Africa. Computer vision models to detect illness through lung X-ray images Python Script to scrape and sort by price selected goods from different online providers Several Data Science and Machine Learning projects 	Beirut, Lebanon
Spring 2018-2019 Fall 2019-2020	 Teaching Assistance (277 hours total) American University of Lebanon (AUB) Teaching Introduction to Programming C++ / Matlab Teaching Computer Organization VHDL/PIC Software Tools (QT/Doxygen/Make Files/Unit Tests) 	Beirut, Lebanon

From 2017 to 2018

Research Intern

University of Versailles (UVSQ)

- Handling Multidimensional Data from Moving Air Pollution Sensors
- Use R libraries to transform data into functions
- Implement a Spark/Scala-based framework to read sensory values, interpolate them into functions, apply analysis on them, ...

Versailles, France

Skills

Languages: Fluent in English and Arabic.

Soft Skills: Communication, Teamwork, Setting Goals, Planning

Technical Skills: Python, Flask, Docker, Django, Scikit Learn, Pytorch, Hugging Face

References

Dr. Wes Masri, Professor at George Mason University, US, wmasri@gmu.edu

Portfolio

For more interesting details check my online portfolio or scan the QR code



Last Updated: August 25